Baibhabi Goswami

| Belfield, Co. Dublin | +353-899469929 | <u>baibhabi.goswami@ucdconnect.ie</u> | | <u>linkedin.com/in/baibhabi-goswami/</u> | | <u>baibhabigoswami.github.io</u> |

Profile

Finance graduate with 7 years' experience in accounting, auditing, financial reporting, and tax planning, now pursuing MSc in Sustainable Finance. Entrepreneurial spirit led to the founding of a financial consulting firm. Expertise in creating fiscally responsible strategies aligned with sustainable practices. Strong analytical skills with excellent interpersonal and communication skills, developed while working with culturally diverse teams. Demonstrates a commitment to driving financial performance alongside positive environmental and social impact.

Education

MSc. in Sustainable Finance	2023 – 2024
UCD Michael Smurfit Graduate Business School, Dublin, Ireland	
Key Modules: Energy Economics & Policy; Sustainable Finance; Renewable Energy Fina	nce;
Applied Derivative Securities; Portfolio and Risk Management.	
Additional Module: Climate Change and Business Sustainability (based on the UNFCCC)).
Association of Chartered Certified Accountants (ACCA-part qualified)	2022-
Completed practical training and 6 out of 13 modules.	
Integrated Professional Competence Exam (CA-Inter)	2016 - 2020
Institute of Chartered Accountants of India, India	
Master's in Commerce (Grade 1:1)	2018 - 2020
Indira Gandhi National Open University, India	
Post-Graduate Diploma in International Business Operations (Grade 1:1)	2018 - 2020
Indira Gandhi National Open University, India	
Bachelor's in Commerce (Grade 1:1, with distinction)	2013 - 2016
Ravenshaw University, Cuttack, India	

Career Experience

Research Assistant, UCD, Dublin, Ireland *Providing support in academic research.*

Nov 2023 -

• Conducted comprehensive literature reviews to underpin current research projects, ensuring robust theoretical foundations.

Proprietor, Chetana Financial Services, New Delhi, India

Nov 2020 – Aug 2023

- Headed a group of 9, orchestrating weekly meetings to tackle and resolve operational challenges, enhancing professional growth, and offering constructive critiques to boost team efficiency.
- Provided tailored direct and indirect tax planning and filing services, achieving up to 90% client retention by focusing on client satisfaction and specific client requirements.
- Expertly crafted forecasted financial statements for client credit applications, consistently achieving a 93% success rate in securing approvals.
- Advocated for fiscally prudent money investment strategies in line with sustainable practices, tailoring guidance to client needs in a financial consultant capacity.

Article Assistant, Raj Aniruddh & Associates, New Delhi, India

Nov 2019 – Oct 2020

- Led the organisation-wide annual balance sheets and income statements finalisation process and corporate reporting, coordinating with cross-functional teams to enhance efficiency and accuracy.
- Enhanced the direct tax services team's performance, successfully implementing strategies that led to a reduction of up to 15% in tax liabilities for select clients while maintaining full compliance.
- Advocated for the adoption of virtual financial services during the COVID-19 period, contributing to the sustenance of client trust and achieving a 7% increase in monthly turnover.

Article Assistant, Arun Malhotra & Associates, New Delhi, India

Nov 2016 - Nov 2019

- Directed a variety of audit engagements, including statutory, tax, stock, and internal audits, and proactively identified errors, preventing a client from incurring a potential fine of INR 2 million once.
- Was integral to a special fraud investigation unit, traced approx. INR 30 million in misappropriated funds, demonstrating sharp analytical skills and a commitment to financial integrity.
- Maintained general ledger integrity, achieving flawless financial records, and reducing cash flow statement reconciliation errors by 40%, thereby enhancing decision-making reliability and adherence to fiscal compliance.
- Streamlined the account closure and finalisation process, cutting down the cycle time by up to 20%, expediting the year-end closing activities, and supporting timely and accurate financial reporting.

Working Paper

• Fiscal Performance & Economic Growth: A cross-state empirical analysis between Tripura and Developed States of India[pdf] (First author).

Additional Skills

- Languages: English (proficient), Bengali (native), Hindi (proficient), Oriya (conversant)
- Programming Language: Julia; MATLAB.
- IT Skills: Oracle; SQL; STATA; LaTeX; Advanced user of Microsoft Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint).
- Certification: Bloomberg; Tally ERP9.

Other Information

- Awards: Kulapati K.M. Munshi Award in Mathematics, Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan (2011); Certificate of Commendation, Shikhan Bharati (2011); Subramaniam Character Certificate, BTVM (2008).
- Achievements: Second rank, Bachelor's in Commerce, Ravenshaw University (2016); AISSCE Commerce State topper (2013); Perfect CGPA (10.0/10.0) in AISSE (2011).
- Volunteer: Ray's Foundation, Odisha (2016-2023).
- Interest: Regional theatre and recitation; received Biswajt Das Memorial Award (2007).